[MUSIC]
[음악]
So classifiers are really trying to make decisions.
분류기는 결정을 내립니다
Decisions as to whether a sentence is positive or negative, or
문장이 긍정적인지 부정적인지
whether a set of lab tests plus x-rays
진단 결과와 x-ray, 분석을 통해 독감인지
plus measurements lead to a certain disease like flu or cold.
감기인지 알아내는 등 말입니다
That's a decision that needs to be made.
이런 결정은 누군가 내려야만 하죠
So let's talk a little bit about how classifiers especially linear classifiers
분류기 중에서도 선형 분류기가 어떻게 결정을
make decisions.
내리는지 알아봅시다
To understand decision boundaries,
결정경계를 이해하기 위해서
suppose you only had two words with non-zero weight.
단어 2개가 0이 아닌 가중치를 갖고 있다고 합시다
You have awesome with positive weight of one and
굉장하다, 양수 가중치 1과
awful which is just awful so it has a negative weight of 1.5.
끔찍하다, 음수 가중치 1.5입니다
If you have this situation then the score is gonna be 1 times the number of
이럴 경우 점수는 1 * 굉장하다 등장 횟수
awesomes in the sentence, minus 1.5 times the number of awfuls.
- 1.5 * 끔찍하다 횟수가 될 겁니다
So we can plot this on an axis, there's the awesome axis and
그래프에 그려볼텐데 굉장하다 축과
then there's the awful axis.
끔찍하다 축으로 이루어져 있습니다
So for example, the sentence, the sushi was awesome,
예를 들어 문장 초밥은 굉장했다
the food was awesome, but the service was awful.
음식은 굉장했다, 하지만 서비스는 끔찍했다
Then that has two awesomes and one awful.
굉장하다 2개과 끔찍하다 1개죠
It's plotted in the point (2,1) on the axis.
그래프 (2,1)에 점을 찍습니다
And similarly for something that has say, three awfuls and one awesome,
비슷한 방식으로 끔찍하다 3개와 굉장하다 1개
and for something that is all awesome, so three awesomes is at a point (3,0),
굉장하다만 3개 있으면 (3,0)에 점을 찍습니다
and so on for other sentences.
다른 문장에도 똑같이 적용합니다
Now, let's understand a little better how we scored the sentences and
문장 점수를 어떻게 매기는지,
what does that imply about our decisions.
결정에 어떤 영향을 끼치는지 더 알아봅시다
So, for example, take the point (3,0) as 3 awesomes, no awfuls.
예를 들어 (3,0) 점은 굉장하다 3개와 끔찍하다 0개입니다
Three awesomes gives you a positive
굉장하다 3개는 긍정적인 예측을
prediction because the score is greater than zero.
안겨주는데 점수가 0보다 크기 때문이죠
And that is true for every point really on the bottom right of the axis.
오른쪽 밑에 있는 모든 점이 그렇습니다
While the points on the top left all have score less than zero so for
왼쪽 위에 있는 모든 점은 0보다 낮은 점수를 가졌는데
example the point three awfuls, one awesome got score less than zero.
예를 들어 끔찍하다 3개와 굉장하다 1개는 0보다 낮은 점수입니다
So, those get labeled negative.
부정적이라는 라벨이 붙는 것이죠
And, in fact, what separates the negative predictions from the positive predictions
부정적인 예측과 긍정적인 예측을 나누는 선은
is the line that defines the places where I don't know what's positive and
긍정인지 부정인지 알 수 없는 지점인데
what's negative, and that's the line where 1.0 #awesome- 1.5 #awful = 0.
1.0 * 굉장하다 횟수 - 1.5 * 끔찍하다의 결과가 0이 되는 곳이죠
And that's the line when, I don't know, the prediction is uncertain, and
이렇게 예측이 불확실해지는 선을
so we call that the decision boundary.
결정경계라고 부릅니다
Everything on one side we predict is positive,
그 선을 기준으로 한쪽은 긍정이고
everything on the other we predict is negative.
다른 쪽은 부정입니다
Now notice that the decision boundary,
결정경계 1.0 * 굉장하다 횟수 -
1.0 times awesome minus 1.5 times awful equals to 0 is a line.
1.5 * 끔찍하다 횟수 0이 직선임을 확인할 수 있습니다
And so that's why it's called a linear classifier.
선형분류기라 불리는 이유죠
It's a linear decision boundary.
선형결정경계입니다
So decision boundaries are what separate the positive
결정경계는 긍정적인 예측과 부정적인
predictions from the negative predictions.
예측을 분리합니다
So, in the case of just two features, we see this is just a line.
특징이 2개인 경우에는 지금과 같이 직선이 됩니다
But that situation will differ as we increase the number of features.
하지만 특징 수가 늘어나면 상황이 달라지죠
So in two dimensions, a linear function is a line.
2차원에서 선형 함수는 직선입니다
In three dimensions, we have three, words for example that have non-zero weight and
3차원에서 예를 들어 3단어가 0가 아닌 가중치를
everything else has zero weight and we get to the plane.
갖고 있으면 평면이 됩니다
And so it's a little hard to draw in 3D, but
3차원으로 그리기는 조금 어렵지만
the positive predictions here are above the plane and the negative predictions
긍정적인 예측은 평면 위에, 부정적인 예측은
here are below the plane and the plane is somehow inclined in the space.
평면 밑에 존재하며 평면은 공간에서 약간 기울어져 있습니다
Now when you have not just three non-zero words but in
실제 애플리케이션에서는 3단어가 아니라
re-application you're gonna have tens of thousands of words with non-zero weight.
수 만 단어가 0이 아닌 가중치를 가질 확률이 높습니다
And in that case we'll call those hyperplanes,
그럴 경우 고차원 분리기를
really high dimensional separators called hyperplanes.
초평면이라고 합니다
Now, of course you can use more than linear classifiers.
물론 선형 분류기만 쓸 수 있는 건 아닙니다
You can use more complex classifiers.
더 복잡한 분류기도 사용할 수 있죠
And those, instead of having lines or
직선, 초평면보다 복잡한 모양과
hyperplanes, they have more complicated shapes or squiggly separations.
구불구불한 구분선을 가지게 됩니다
And we're gonna learn more about that in the classification course.
분류 강의에서 자세히 배웁니다
>> [MUSIC]
[음악]